in the next cycle in cycle 10 this
instruction will be able to dispatch
this is our ad and it's going to execute
in Cycles 10 and 11 so in cycle 12 is
going to try to write its result so in
cycle 11 nothing really happens other
than the execution of these two
instructions but in cycle 12 what's
going to happen is this instruction is
going to broadcast this result so we
will Mark that it Broast the result we
will find the register that matches ad2
which is F6 and overwrite the value of
F6 with the new value which is the - 9.6
plus -
2.5 so it's going to be
-12.1 so this is the value of
ad2 and now we're going to un rename
this to make future accesses read the
new F6 and uh no instructions was
waiting for not that this was the last
instruction in a sequence so nobody was
really waiting for this result but this
instruction is done now so we can free
this reservation station now nothing
will really happen until cycle 17 in
cycle 17 this multiply is finally going
to broadcast its result we're
multiplying 2.5 * 2.5 and then you know
minus and that value goes into F0 so F0
is going to become whatever that result
is we're not going to even try to
compute that it's going to be unram here
it's going to put that value over here
and now the Divide is finally ready to
go and we're going to free this
reservation station so finally in cycle
18 The Divide is ready to go it's been
dispatched add 40 Cycles so it's going
to be in cycle 58 that we finally
produce that result so nothing really
happens until cycle 58 at which point
this value is broadcast register F10
gets to grab that value we un rename
this we free this reservation station we
look at who is waiting for it but nobody
is and that concludes our example